NGUYEN HOANG VIET

Mobile Software Engineer (Junior)





ABOUT MYSELF

I am working as a Mobile Developer (React Native) with more than 1 year of experience. Recently, I've been doing more research on Flutter and have worked on several projects that use the Bloc pattern.

I have positive attitude and can execute on difficult tasks. I am always energetic and eager to learn new skills or share about IT knowledge. Ability to work independently as well as in a team with high responsibility.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Mobile developer

ITBee-Solutions | 11/2020 - Present

Working as mobile developer.

- The main person initiate the project, base config (Redux, Restful Api, Base Components...), build the source's structure, merge code, resolve the React-native's problem with team's members...
- · Training for new interns
- Joining and learning Swift to maintain iOS project with mobile project manager.

Internship / Fresher Mobile developer

Ant-Tech | 05/2020 - 10/2020

Internship process as mobile dev position.

- Using React-native with Hook, Redux Saga, folder constructed according to Ignite boilerplate. How to upgrade new React-native's version, upgrade new library's version.
- · Using TypeScript / ES6 syntax, refactor code to look cleaner
- · More Git skills: Stash, revert, merge, config handle
- Building new Android and iOS (Xcode) version, build and test Android bundle with bundle tool
- Daily report, meeting skill, write report document, resolve the problem...

Student / Working with my teacher

09/2019 - 05/2020

The first time to join and work with real project. Understanding the process of product (from initiation to release) working with BA, dev, tester, designer...

- My first meet with React Native, Redux / Redux observable, Components, Props / States, React Native's lifecycle
- JavaScript syntax, how to work (run, debug...) with React Native
- Apply Git's skills to manager real project's source code

TYPICAL PROJECTS

DAYGO

08/2021 - present

Project Description: DayGo delivery app is a connection platform between businesses and drivers, an application for shippers, helping shippers to manage and track their work as well as help administrators track delivery activities more easily right away on the phone

Mobile team size: 2 (App reference: iOS, Android)

KBIT

07/2021 - 09/2021

Project Description: BEE AFFILIATE SYSTEM Comprehensive argument transfer solution to help businesses manage and expand distribution channels, agents, collaborators, memberships and affiliates effectively

 $\textbf{Mobile team size:}\ 2\ (\mathsf{App\ reference:iOS,\,Android}\)$

BeeBeauty

02/2021 - 08/2021

Project Description: BeeBeauty is an application with main features are Spa schedule booking, sell products, manage customer's information for Spa chain system.

Mobile team size: 3 (App reference: iOS, Android)

Responsibilities:

- Mobile project's leader (Assign tasks, solve problems and guide for team's members. Error handler in development process...)
- Initiating project, config base, core (Redux, Redux-Saga, Service, build folder structure following Ignite pattern, create common base components...)
- Fixing bug, refactor code, researching to optimization structures, performance and manage source code with Git (Merge code, conflict handle, basic review...)
- Building iOS version to TestFlight and Android (apk, aab)
- Deploying applications to App Store and Google Play Store.

 $\textbf{Inside the projects:} \ \textbf{Ignite pattern structure, Redux-Saga, TypeScript, Hook, react-native-config, one-signal, firebase, and the projects is a supplied to the projects of the project of$

SKILLS

Technical

Mobile Applications

React native / Flutter

Redux / Bloc

JavaScript / TypeScript / Dart

Worked with iOS / Swift

Self Skills

Communicate effectively

Team player

Problem solving

Knowledge

Understanding about the Product Management Process

Understanding about software design, some design patterns. RestfulAPI

Having experience working with Firebase, Notification, Socket.io, Deploy app...

EDUCATION

Software Engineer

Ho Chi Minh City Vocational Training College 2017 - 2020

LANGUAGES

Vietnamese (Native)

English (Reading, Basic Speaking, Writing)

INTERESTS

Reading, Watching and Listening

Play sports (Badminton, Gym...)

Photography

ACTIVITIES

15km Finisher

LAAN Ultra trial 2019 (2019)

otp, notification, google map...

AnyBackup

01/2021 - 02/2021

Project Description: AnyBackup is an iOS IOT application using with auto-backup device (can connect with USB or SD card) to backup or restores data (photos, music ...) from iPhone to auto-backup devices and vice

Mobile team size: 2

Responsibilities:

- Researching, Building UI and features following customer's requirements
- Fixing bugs, refactoring code, building new version..

Inside the project: Swift 5, SnapKit, MVC design pattern

Polymate

05/2020 - 10/2020

Project Description: Polymate is a social network which has the particularity of relying on a news feed $developed \ by \ its \ own \ users, \ which \ changes \ in \ real \ time \ taking \ into \ account \ the \ geolocated \ position \ of \ the$

Mobile team size: 4 (in Viet Nam, reference: polymate.fr/nous)

Responsibilities:

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Support and recommend the way to resolve the problems, new feature ideas directly with client.}$
- · Building new screen, working with Restful API.
- Fixing bug, refactor code and manager source code with Git.
- Building iOS version to TestFlight and Android (apk, aab).
- Writing documentation for future maintainers.

 $\textbf{Inside the project:} \ \textbf{Ignite pattern structure,} \ \textbf{Redux-Saga,} \ \textbf{TypeScript,} \ \textbf{Hook,} \ \textbf{react-native-config,} \ \textbf{one-signal...}$

PERSONAL PROJECTS

EnglishVocab

Project description: I have developed this application for play mini game to learn english. This application can $login\ with\ Google\ account, message\ together\ and\ available\ on\ Google\ Play\ now\ (in\ the\ process\ to\ develope$

 $\textbf{Project's target:} \ \ \text{Working with SQLite to save and query data, crawl data with Jsoup, Google Services to} \\$ develope message, notification feature...

Improve logic handle skill and mindset to resolve the problems.

Deploying app to Google Play and more...

Reference: Available on Play Store



You can find more my personal projects was public on My Github (+50 repositories) . All of them are developed when I have free time or after my work hours on the purpose of practicing skills or learning something new.